Jesse Hogan

Software Developer

jessehogan0@gmail.com

Summary

I have been a software developer for 15 years. I use a wide variety of technologies such as C#, PHP and SQL Server, and I have a strong knowledge-base of other applications and languages. Therefore, I am seeking an opportunity to use my talents and experience to develop and deliver fast, efficient, and high-quality code to my clients.

Experience

Software Developer at Glynlyon Inc.

May 2008 - May 2016 (8 years 1 month)

As a WordPress/PHP developer, I built and maintained several public facing sites. The software was developed using PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML and CSS. The e-commerce sites used Magento. Other sites used WordPress in a Pantheon environment. Source code was maintained in Subversion and Git repositories. I built and maintained a custom WebService proxy in PHP so the WordPress sites could generate leads in the Microsoft CRM server.

I was a member of a software development team that develops and maintains an learning management system (LMS) (grades 3 through 12). The user interface is written in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery. The business tier is written in PHP with a custom-built MVC framework. It uses Doctrine as an object-relational mapper to interface with a MySQL back-end.

I also supported and developed a similar software product that uses Microsoft and open source technologies. For back-end operations, we use SQL Server 2005/2008 accessed through direct ODBC calls and through a Web Services interface. The business tier is developed in C# and VB.NET. The front end is chiefly comprised of HTML/CSS, jQuery and WinForms. Multimedia offerings, such as videos and games, are implemented in Flash and HTML5. Reports are implemented in Crystal Reports. We use Subversion and Git for source control.

Working with the Curriculum Development department, I wrote scripts to automate the file management, validation, correction, reporting, source control management (Subversion), and deployment (server and CD) of a vast number of XML files. This is done using Bash, Python, Visual Basic and C#.

My database administrative activities include creating and maintaining scripts written in Bash and Python to automate the code-generation of SQL scripts which perform the task of database schema migrations. I also maintain a GUI utility which allows tech-support and customers to easily perform database administrative tasks against production databases.

Lead Software Developer at Direct Alliance Corporation

March 2001 - January 2008 (6 years 11 months)

- * I was team-lead of a department which develops, maintains and optimizes a 3-tiered, internationalized, web-based, telesales ERP system for an overseas client using chiefly Microsoft technologies (ASP, .NET, SQL Server).
- * I wrote and maintained a desktop application to automate the source control management (CVS and Subversion) and source code deployment of several web and text-based applications for several different clients.
- * I maintain a Perl middleware program in a Linux environment responsible for file transfers (usually over FTP or SFTP) from servers in external networks to local servers and visa-versa.
- * I wrote software to archive sales order records (along with child records from hundreds of child tables) to an archive database server.

Software Developer at ITMETRIXX

January 2000 - June 2001 (1 year 6 months)

* I developed a ticketing system to be utilized from various locations for Sun Health, Inc., a major corporation with multiple client sites. This project included use of Microsoft Access interfacing with a MySQL back-end running on a Linux platform. The system effectively managed entry of hardware hot swap orders and technical support issues.

Database Application Developer at Inacom

1998 - 2000 (2 years)

Wrote software to manage warehouse inventory and track technical issues. System was implemented in Microsoft Access.

I wrote a system for Human Resources operations. System was written in Microsoft Access and used Excel Automation for reporting.

Technical Consultant at Microage

1998 - 1998 (less than a year)

I diagnosed connectivity problems for US West ADSL routers in the technical support department. Performed advanced troubleshooting daily.

I interacted extensively with US West customers to identify issues.

I performed sales activities to secure new business for DSL routers.

Education

Tempe High School

High School Diploma, 1990 - 1994

Interests

Staying informed on new technologies and regular self-learning to stay ahead in my field. I also have an interest in future technologies, such as business intelligence, data mining, and machine learning.

I am an avid reader, and I enjoy being in the outdoors with my family hiking, camping, swimming, etc...

Languages

English

Skills & Expertise

C#

PHP

Perl

VB.NET

ASP.NET

Python

Bash Shell

AWK

Sed

SQL

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

Linux

Microsoft Windows

Apache

MySQL

Microsoft SQL Server

IIS

Subversion

CVS

Object Oriented Design

Configuration Management

Git

Jenkins

NUnit

Sikuli

MVC Architecture

jQuery

SFTP

SSH

Crystal Reports

HTML5

AngularJS

XML

ORM

CSLA

ASP.NET MVC

Bash

WordPress

Certifications

Learn AngularJS 2: The Basics

Lynda.com License F484CE April 2016 to April 2016

Jesse Hogan

Software Developer

jessehogan0@gmail.com



Contact Jesse on LinkedIn